<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://notes.lincheng.uk</id>
    <title>林的学习笔记</title>
    <updated>2022-12-21T22:43:38.094Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://notes.lincheng.uk"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://notes.lincheng.uk/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>温故而知新</subtitle>
    <logo>https://notes.lincheng.uk/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://notes.lincheng.uk/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2022, 林的学习笔记</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why the Best Leaders May Not be Interested in Leading Positions: Insights from Elon Musk and Lei Jun]]></title>
        <id>https://notes.lincheng.uk/post/why-the-best-leaders-may-not-be-interested-in-leading-positions-insights-from-elon-musk-and-lei-jun/</id>
        <link href="https://notes.lincheng.uk/post/why-the-best-leaders-may-not-be-interested-in-leading-positions-insights-from-elon-musk-and-lei-jun/">
        </link>
        <updated>2022-12-21T06:34:19.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk made this comment in a recent interview and Xiaomi CEO Lei Jun had the exact experience in the early days when he was at the Kingsoft.</p>
<p>So what is the underlying reason for this?</p>
<p>There are several reasons why the best leaders may not be interested in leading positions.</p>
<p>First, the best leaders may already be fulfilled in their current roles and may not feel the need to seek out a leadership position. They may be content with the work they are doing and the impact they are having, and may not see the value in taking on additional responsibilities.</p>
<p>Second, the best leaders may not be interested in the additional stress and pressure that comes with a leadership role. Leading a team or organization can be demanding and time-consuming, and some individuals may not be willing to take on this level of commitment.</p>
<p>Third, the best leaders may have a specific vision or mission that they are passionate about, and they may not want to be held back by the constraints of a leadership role. They may prefer to work independently or in small groups where they have more freedom to pursue their goals.</p>
<p>Finally, the best leaders may not be interested in the politics and bureaucracy that often come with leadership positions. They may prefer to work in environments where they can focus on the work itself, rather than getting caught up in power struggles and office politics.</p>
<p>Overall, the best leaders may not be interested in leading positions for a variety of reasons, including a lack of desire for additional responsibilities, a preference for their current role, a desire to pursue a specific vision or mission, and a dislike for politics and bureaucracy.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Deliver Value to the End User by Reducing Costs and Increasing Quality]]></title>
        <id>https://notes.lincheng.uk/post/how-to-deliver-value-to-the-end-user-by-reducing-costs-and-increasing-quality/</id>
        <link href="https://notes.lincheng.uk/post/how-to-deliver-value-to-the-end-user-by-reducing-costs-and-increasing-quality/">
        </link>
        <updated>2022-12-21T05:57:18.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://notes.lincheng.uk/post-images/1671661329978.png" alt="" loading="lazy"><br>
In order to successfully deliver on a need for the end user, it is important to identify their specific need and determine an affordable price for it. In this example, the need is a cleaned floor and the end user is willing to pay 10 GBP per week for it. However, the cost to deliver on this need may be higher, such as the estimated 1000 GBP to build a cleaning robot.</p>
<p>To make the product more affordable for the end user, it is necessary to investigate the components and determine if there are any areas where costs can be reduced. In this case, the camera component of the robot is too expensive due to the high cost of the glass. By finding a new and unique way to manufacture the glass at a lower cost, such as through a different manufacturing process, it is possible to reduce the overall cost of the product.</p>
<p>To make the product even more affordable, it is important to produce it at scale to take advantage of the cost savings from mass production. The ultimate goal is to create a product with better quality at a cheaper price for the end user. Overall, the key to success is to find creative solutions to reduce costs and deliver value to the customer.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 Simple Ways to Boost Dopamine Naturally: Exercise, Diet, Sleep, Pleasure, and Supplements]]></title>
        <id>https://notes.lincheng.uk/post/5-simple-ways-to-Boost-Dopamine-Naturally/</id>
        <link href="https://notes.lincheng.uk/post/5-simple-ways-to-Boost-Dopamine-Naturally/">
        </link>
        <updated>2022-03-12T04:52:50.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://notes.lincheng.uk/post-images/1671658622027.png" alt="" loading="lazy"><br>
Dopamine is a neurotransmitter that plays a key role in the brain's reward and pleasure centers. It is involved in a variety of important functions, including motivation, attention, learning, and movement.</p>
<p>There are several ways to increase dopamine levels in the brain, including the following:</p>
<p>Exercise: Physical activity has been shown to increase dopamine levels, particularly high-intensity exercises such as running and weight lifting.</p>
<p>Eat a healthy diet: Consuming a diet that is rich in fruits, vegetables, and lean proteins can help to increase dopamine levels.</p>
<p>Get enough sleep: Adequate sleep is essential for maintaining healthy dopamine levels.</p>
<p>Engage in activities that bring pleasure: Doing things that bring you joy, such as listening to music, spending time with loved ones, or pursuing hobbies, can help to increase dopamine levels.</p>
<p>Try natural supplements: Some natural supplements, such as tyrosine and L-dopa, can help to increase dopamine levels. It is important to consult with a healthcare professional before taking any supplements.</p>
<p>It is worth noting that excessive dopamine release can lead to negative consequences, such as addiction, and it is important to maintain healthy levels of dopamine in the brain.</p>
<p>In conclusion, there are several ways to increase dopamine levels in the brain, including exercise, a healthy diet, enough sleep, engaging in pleasurable activities, and trying natural supplements. It is important to maintain healthy dopamine levels and to seek the advice of a healthcare professional before taking any supplements.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[零基预算法]]></title>
        <id>https://notes.lincheng.uk/post/ling-ji-yu-suan-fa-yi-ge-qiang-da-de-si-kao-gong-ju/</id>
        <link href="https://notes.lincheng.uk/post/ling-ji-yu-suan-fa-yi-ge-qiang-da-de-si-kao-gong-ju/">
        </link>
        <updated>2022-03-08T00:35:15.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="什么是零基预算法">什么是零基预算法？</h1>
<p>零基预算法(Zero-based budgeting)是指每一个会计周期，开支都不从原有的基础出发。而是一切从零开始，审核每一笔开支的必要性。</p>
<h1 id="为什么要使用零基预算法">为什么要使用零基预算法？</h1>
<p>因为这个方法可以帮我们更好的集中精力，把注意力放在有最大产出的事情上，从而产生更大的影响力。</p>
<h1 id="零基预算法最大的优缺点">零基预算法最大的优缺点？</h1>
<p>零基预算法最大的优点是敏捷，也就是不认为上年的每个支出项目都是必要的。从而更好的适应新的环境变化。<br>
零基预算法最大的缺点是费时，因为一切工作都要从头开始，所以制定预算所需要的时间更长。</p>
<h1 id="零基预算法怎么用在个人生活里">零基预算法怎么用在个人生活里？</h1>
<ol>
<li>问自己如下问题——已知我现在所知的所有信息，是否有任何我现在在做的事情，我重新开始的话就不会再去做？</li>
<li>找出这件事情，然后及时止损。想好要怎么停，需要多久停。</li>
<li>回到1，继续寻找下一件事情。</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="举例">举例：</h1>
<p>如果当初我知道这个人是这样的话，我就不会和他(她)交往。=》果断分手。<br>
如果当初知道这个员工是这样的话，我就不会雇佣他(她)。=》果断解雇。<br>
如果当初知道这个公司是这样的话，我就不会加入公司。=》果断离职。</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
        <id>https://notes.lincheng.uk/post/hello-world/</id>
        <link href="https://notes.lincheng.uk/post/hello-world/">
        </link>
        <updated>2022-03-03T18:37:18.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!-- more -->
<h1 id="this-post-is-to-mark-the-point-to-add-the-gitalk-commenting-system">This post is to mark the point to add the gitalk commenting system.</h1>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Test]]></title>
        <id>https://notes.lincheng.uk/post/test/</id>
        <link href="https://notes.lincheng.uk/post/test/">
        </link>
        <updated>2022-02-28T12:35:50.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Test article.</p>
<h1 id="this-is-a-great-article">THis is a great article</h1>
<h2 id="it-starts-with-one-sentence">It starts with one sentence</h2>
<h2 id="then-another">Then another</h2>
<h2 id="then-another-2">Then another</h2>
<h2 id="and-it-ends-here">And it ends here.</h2>
<p><em>What you might say</em></p>
<p>Yes. It is expected and clear as this.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>